Martez Howard

SUMMARY

To give you a brief overview of my skill set – For over five years I have been working in software engineering obtaining various roles and contributing to a multitude of projects. I specialize in consumer-facing applications and enjoy focusing my career on building maintainable, scalable systems in which the UI communicates with the data model. My wide ranged knowledge and skill set is focused on full stack development including highly used tools in development such as docker and kubernetes for scalability and infrastructure setup.

EXPERIENCE

Endpoint Closing, Inc - Full Stack Engineer

September 2019 – May 2020

Developing at Endpoint Closing I worked remotely on their product website and mobile application. Majority of the tasks involved adding new features onto both the website and the mobile application for the consumer to have a seamless experience handling their entire escrow transactions.

- Test and build both react and react native components
- Update docker container structure for local development
- Share thoughts and ideas with the team

Presence Product Group, LLC - Full Stack Engineer

March 2018 - October 2019

Developing and consulting at Presence in San Francisco on high-profile consumer-facing applications. Many of the projects were built using React on the front end and Nodejs, PHP, or Python on the back end using Docker containers and CircleCi for integration.

- Test and build both front end and backend infrastructure
- Share thoughts and ideas with the team
- Test and build components for consumer experience

Airlitix - Front End Engineer

February 2018 - April 2018

Airlitix is a rapidly growing startup, revolutionizing the indoor security and utility ecosystem. The project is built using React on the front end.

• Restructure front end design of site to be more visually modern

Freelance - Full Stack Engineer

May 2016 - Current

Search for clients and handle aspects of the development close with web design. Many of the projects are built using React on the front end and Nodejs on the back end along with setting up container servers.

Create web applications using various technologies

(916) 385-7437 Gigs4martez@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/martezhoward-b38038108

GitHub

https://github.com/dizthewize

https://martezhoward.com

SKILLS

Front End development

TypeScript, React, React Native, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Redux, Tailwind, Sass/SCSS, Less, styledcomponents

DevOps technologies

Docker, AWS, Azure, Terraform, Ansible, Prometheus, Jest, Linux, Powershell, Kubernetes, Jenkins, TravisCi, CircleCi, Git, Redis

Full Stack development

NodeJS, PHP, Express, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgresQL, GraphQL, Python

EDUCATION

American River College Business Admin. Marketing

CSU - Sacramento
Business Admin. Marketing